NULL:  Every gap, every shortcut, every forgotten door -
I will find it.
VEGA:  Not tonight. Welcome to the Aegis Citadel. I'm
Vega, and I'll be your guide.
Every modern organization runs on information. Protect it,
and you thrive. Lose it, and you fall.
VEGA:  Picture an organization's information as a walled city.
At its heart sits the Crown Data -
the records, secrets, and services everyone depends on.
NULL:  I don't want your walls. I want what
they guard - the Crown Data. And trust?
Trust shatters so easily.
NOVA:  I'm Nova - just started here, and honestly?
I'm new to all of this. Can we
start from the very beginning?
VEGA:  We will. First, a few words everyone uses
and almost no one defines.
NOVA:  Okay, so who writes all this stuff?
VEGA:  That would be NIST. Think of them as
the standards lab for digital defense.
VEGA:  The thing we're protecting is an information system.
NOVA:  So... not just a computer?
VEGA:  Far more. The people and processes count too.
NOVA:  And a 'control' is...?
VEGA:  A safeguard. Something deliberate that reduces risk. NIST
SP 800-53 is a giant, organized catalog of
them.
NOVA:  People keep throwing around this word, 'risk.'
VEGA:  Risk is likelihood times impact. A threat is
who or what could hurt you; a vulnerability
is the weakness they'd use; risk is the
chance - and the cost - if they
do.
VEGA:  Every control in the catalog serves three goals.
Remember them as C-I-A.
VEGA:  Confidentiality - keep secrets secret. Integrity - keep
data correct and untampered. Availability - keep it
working when you need it.
NOVA:  Confidentiality, Integrity, Availability - so that's what every
guardian is really protecting?
NOVA:  But why do we even need all this?
VEGA:  A law says you must protect systems. A
catalog lists what you can use. A framework
is the process that connects them.
VEGA:  The law is FISMA - the Federal Information
Security Modernization Act. 800-53 is the catalog. The
RMF is the process. Hold those three apart,
and everything else clicks.
NOVA:  Isn't privacy just part of security?
VEGA:  They overlap, but they aim at different things.
In Revision 5, security and privacy finally share
one catalog.
NOVA:  Eight-hundred fifty-three - that's the catalog, right? What's
actually in it?
VEGA:  Hundreds of controls, organized into families - a
menu you put to work.
VEGA:  The catalog is organized into twenty families. We'll
walk them as twenty districts of the city.
VEGA:  A district isn't really a place - it's
a family of related safeguards: policies, processes, and
technical controls.
NOVA:  Twenty? That's a lot of ground.
VEGA:  So we'll group them into six layers of
defense. By the end, you'll remember every one.
VEGA:  Every control shares the same anatomy. Learn it
once, and you can read them all.
VEGA:  First the identifier, like AC-6 - the family
and a number.
VEGA:  Then the control itself: the requirement, what you
must actually do.
NOVA:  And what's the 'discussion' part for?
VEGA:  It gives context and rationale - helpful, but
not itself a requirement.
VEGA:  Related controls point to neighbors. Enhancements add strength
- for example, AC-6 enhancement 1. References point
outside the catalog.
VEGA:  Here's a single control. AC-6, Least Privilege.
NOVA:  Clean. An ID, a title, and what it
means.
VEGA:  When you see a gold card, the Archivist
is reading the catalog's real words - word
for word.
ARCHIVIST:  Employ the principle of least privilege, allowing only
authorized accesses for users (or processes acting on
behalf of users) that are necessary to accomplish
assigned organizational tasks.
NOVA:  People keep saying 'baseline' - what's that mean?
VEGA:  A starting kit of controls - Low, Moderate,
or High, sized to the stakes.
NOVA:  Wait - Low, Moderate, High... where do those
baselines actually live?
VEGA:  Good eye. In Revision 5 they moved out,
into a companion book: 800-53B.
800-53 is the catalog of controls. 800-53B holds
the baselines and tailoring guidance.
VEGA:  800-53 doesn't stand alone. It plugs into a
process called the Risk Management Framework.
VEGA:  In plain terms: prepare, decide how much the
system matters, pick controls, put them in place,
check they work, get a leader to approve
it, then watch it forever.
NOVA:  So the catalog's 800-53, and 800-53B's baselines help
pick where we start?
VEGA:  We'll walk all seven steps in Act Two.
For now, just know the catalog has a
home.
Three guides ride with you.
NULL:  ...and one rides against you.
VEGA:  Six layers lie ahead. The Outer Walls. The
Watchtowers. The Keepers of the Pact.
VEGA:  The High Council. The Forge. The Vaults and
Lifelines. Then the finale: Siege Night.
One honest note before we ride out.
VEGA:  The story is ours. The control text is
theirs - real, and shown on screen.
VEGA:  Let's make it stick. What's a control?
In plain terms, a security 'control' is best
described as:
Your options. A. A type of computer. B.
A safeguard that reduces risk. C. A government
agency.
NOVA:  Pause here and lock in your answer.
VEGA:  The answer is B. A safeguard that reduces
risk. A control is a safeguard or countermeasure
- it reduces risk to the system and
its data.
NOVA:  Quick check. Where do the baselines live now?
Where do the Low, Moderate, and High control
baselines live now?
Your options. A. In 800-53 itself. B. In
NIST SP 800-53B. C. In the RMF.
NOVA:  Pause here and lock in your answer.
VEGA:  The answer is B. In NIST SP 800-53B.
In Revision 5 the Low, Moderate, and High
baselines moved out into companion volume 800-53B.
VEGA:  And how many families guard our city?
How many control families does 800-53 Revision 5
have?
Your options. A. Twelve. B. Seventeen. C. Twenty.
NOVA:  Pause here and lock in your answer.
VEGA:  The answer is C. Twenty. Revision 5 organizes
its controls into twenty families.
NOVA:  Notebook open. That's the whole map on one
page.
VEGA:  That's your foundation. Next, we ride for the
Outer Walls.
NULL:  I'll be waiting at the gate.