NULL:  Every gap, every shortcut, every forgotten door -
I will find it.
VEGA:  Not tonight. One stolen login should never be
enough to end a city.
NOVA:  So where do we begin?
VEGA:  Where every attacker does - at the wall.
NULL:  Every fortress has a door. I only need
one careless soul to leave one open.
VEGA:  Then meet the three guardians of the gate.
I'm Vega. This is the apprentice, Nova.
NOVA:  Let's walk the walls.
VEGA:  Layer one is the perimeter, who gets in,
and what they may touch.
Three families stand the wall: Access Control, Identification,
and Physical.
VEGA:  Three districts light up the map: AC, IA,
and PE.
NOVA:  The gatekeepers of the city.
VEGA:  First, the Gatekeeper, Access Control.
VEGA:  It decides who may enter, and exactly what
they may touch.
VEGA:  In the real world, that's the policies and
mechanisms deciding which users and processes may use
which systems and data.
NOVA:  Where does access begin?
VEGA:  With accounts. AC-2 governs every account from birth
to deletion.
VEGA:  Then the rule that saves you again and
again, AC-6, Least Privilege.
NULL:  Less for them to give me when I
take an account...
ARCHIVIST:  Employ the principle of least privilege, allowing only
authorized accesses for users (or processes acting on
behalf of users) that are necessary to accomplish
assigned organizational tasks.
VEGA:  Every request runs the same path: a policy
decides, and a gate enforces it.
VEGA:  Say Alice works in payroll. Policy lets her
open payroll records; the same gate blocks Bob
from marketing.
NOVA:  Decide, then enforce. AC-3 is the enforcement.
VEGA:  Lock these three into memory.
VEGA:  Say the Gatekeeper's oath with me. None pass
unknown; none hold more than they need.
VEGA:  Next, the Seal-Bearer, Identification and Authentication.
NOVA:  Access Control trusts a name. This guardian proves
the name is real.
VEGA:  IA-2 demands proof of identity for every organizational
user.
VEGA:  Its enhancements - like IA-2(1) and IA-2(2) -
are where multi-factor authentication lives.
NOVA:  Multi-factor authentication - what is that, exactly?
VEGA:  Two kinds of proof instead of one. It's
why the pipeline breach we opened with would
have failed.
NOVA:  And the passwords and tokens themselves?
VEGA:  IA-5 manages them, strength, rotation, protection.
ARCHIVIST:  Uniquely identify and authenticate organizational users and associate
that unique identification with processes acting on behalf
of those users.
VEGA:  Identity first. Always.
VEGA:  The Seal-Bearer's oath. Prove the name, or the
gate stays shut.
VEGA:  Last on the wall, the Wall-Warden, Physical and
Environmental Protection.
NULL:  Why pick a lock... when I can walk
through an open door?
VEGA:  In reality, PE is physical access control -
guards, badges, locks - plus protection from hazards
like fire, power loss, and water.
VEGA:  PE-3 enforces physical access at the doors themselves.
NOVA:  Tailgating, propped doors, lost badges, this is where
you stop them.
VEGA:  And PE-6 watches and logs who comes and
goes.
ARCHIVIST:  Enforce physical access authorizations at [entry and exit
points] by:
VEGA:  Physical security is security.
VEGA:  And the Wall-Warden's oath. A door is a
decision - and I decide.
VEGA:  Remember the framework? The wall is where you
implement what you selected.
NOVA:  Select from the baseline, implement here, assess later.
NOVA:  Guardian check. Who proves your identity? Pause, and
answer.
Which guardian proves you are who you claim,
before you pass?
Your options. A. AC - Access Control. B.
IA - Identification & Authentication. C. PE -
Physical.
NOVA:  Pause here and lock in your answer.
VEGA:  The answer is B. IA - Identification &
Authentication. Identification and Authentication proves who you are
before you're let in.
VEGA:  And the rule that limits the blast radius?
'Only the access you truly need' is which
control?
Your options. A. AC-2 Account Management. B. AC-6
Least Privilege. C. IA-5 Authenticator Management.
NOVA:  Pause here and lock in your answer.
VEGA:  The answer is B. AC-6 Least Privilege. AC-6,
Least Privilege, grants only the access someone truly
needs - nothing more.
NOVA:  Scenario: someone tailgates into the server room. Whose
watch is that?
An intruder tailgates through a propped door into
the server room. Which family should stop it?
Your options. A. PE - Physical. B. AU
- Audit. C. SR - Supply Chain.
NOVA:  Pause here and lock in your answer.
VEGA:  The answer is A. PE - Physical. Physical
and Environmental Protection stops tailgating into the room
itself.
NOVA:  Notebook: the wall is access, identity, and physical
- working together.
VEGA:  Three guardians, one wall. The perimeter holds.
NULL:  Fine. I'll stop knocking... and start hiding.
VEGA:  Then we'll need the watchtowers. Next time.