NULL:  Every log, every record, every trace - I
will erase it.
VEGA:  Not tonight. Even if you slip in, you
will not move unseen.
NOVA:  Because someone's watching?
VEGA:  Because the watchtowers never sleep.
NULL:  I slipped a careless credential past your wall.
Now I move in the shadows.
VEGA:  Shadows don't last here. The watchtowers never sleep.
VEGA:  Layer two assumes someone got in. Now we
see them, stop the rot, and respond.
Three families keep watch: Audit, System Integrity, and
Incident Response.
NOVA:  AU, SI, and IR. The eyes, the immune
system, and the firefighters.
VEGA:  The Chronicler, Audit and Accountability.
VEGA:  It records every footstep, so no deed goes
unseen.
VEGA:  In reality, that's logging security-relevant events so you
can review them and hold people accountable.
NOVA:  What exactly is a 'log'?
VEGA:  A diary the system keeps. A Windows Event
Log, a syslog, a tool like Splunk -
same idea.
VEGA:  AU-2 chooses what's worth logging.
NULL:  So I'll just delete the logs when I'm
done.
VEGA:  Not so fast. AU-9 protects the logs themselves.
NOVA:  So the Null can't quietly rewrite history.
ARCHIVIST:  Identify the types of events that the system
is capable of logging in support of the
audit function:
VEGA:  A log no one reads, or one that
can be erased, is no log at all.
VEGA:  The Chronicler's oath. Every footstep written; no page
erased.
VEGA:  The Healer, System and Information Integrity.
NOVA:  It finds the rot, cures the sickness, and
keeps the truth true.
VEGA:  In reality, that's patching flaws, blocking malicious code,
monitoring for intrusions, and verifying nothing was tampered
with.
VEGA:  SI-2 is flaw remediation, the discipline of patching.
VEGA:  And SI-4 watches the system for signs of
an intruder.
NULL:  Another tower turns? Tedious. Every chain of watchers
has a blind link - and I will
slip through it.
NULL:  Six days I moved in your shadows before
a single tower turned.
NOVA:  Six days?!
VEGA:  Six days - but SI-4 saw the anomaly,
and AU-9 kept the logs he tripped. He
got in. He did not get out clean.
NULL:  ...this time.
ARCHIVIST:  Identify, report, and correct system flaws;
VEGA:  Integrity is keeping the system clean and honest.
VEGA:  The Healer's oath. Find the rot, close the
wound, keep it true.
VEGA:  The Firewatch, Incident Response.
VEGA:  When something burns, it sounds the alarm and
contains the blaze.
VEGA:  In reality, that's detecting, reporting, analyzing, containing, and
recovering from security incidents.
NOVA:  When does a threat become an 'incident'?
VEGA:  The moment it stops being hypothetical - malware
runs, data leaks, a system goes down.
NOVA:  What happens the moment we spot the Null?
VEGA:  IR-4 takes over, handling the incident end to
end.
VEGA:  Every incident follows a rhythm: prepare, detect, contain,
eradicate, recover.
NOVA:  And IR-8 writes the plan that makes it
routine.
ARCHIVIST:  Implement an incident handling capability for incidents that
is consistent with the incident response plan and
includes preparation, detection and analysis, containment, eradication, and
recovery;
VEGA:  The best responders practiced before the fire.
VEGA:  The Firewatch's oath. When it burns, we are
already running.
VEGA:  Selecting and implementing was the wall. Watching is
how you keep it.
NOVA:  Scenario: the Null deletes logs. What stops it?
Pause, and answer.
An intruder tries to delete the logs to
hide. Which control blocks that?
Your options. A. AU-2 Event Logging. B. AU-9
Protection of Audit Information. C. SI-4 System Monitoring.
NOVA:  Pause here and lock in your answer.
VEGA:  The answer is B. AU-9 Protection of Audit
Information. AU-9, Protection of Audit Information, keeps an
intruder from deleting or altering the logs.
VEGA:  And who runs toward the fire?
Which family detects, contains, and recovers from a
breach?
Your options. A. IR - Incident Response. B.
AU - Audit. C. AC - Access Control.
NOVA:  Pause here and lock in your answer.
VEGA:  The answer is A. IR - Incident Response.
Incident Response is the family that detects, contains,
and recovers from a breach.
NOVA:  Notebook: assume they got in, then see them,
heal the system, and answer fast.
VEGA:  Seen, healed, and answered. The towers hold.
NULL:  Then I'll turn your own people against you.
VEGA:  Then we ride to the Keepers of the
Pact.