NULL:  Every gap, every shortcut, every forgotten door -
I will find it.
VEGA:  Not tonight. And the easiest door of all
is a person who hasn't been trained.
NOVA:  So the people are the perimeter too?
VEGA:  The most-attacked one. Let's defend them.
NULL:  Walls and towers? Tedious. People are so much
easier to fool.
VEGA:  Which is why the strongest controls guard the
people, and their data.
VEGA:  Layer three is human. Train them, trust them
carefully, and honor their data.
Three families keep the pact: Awareness & Training,
Personnel Security, and Privacy.
NOVA:  AT, PS, and PT. The teacher, the oathkeeper,
and the privacy herald.
VEGA:  The Drillmaster, Awareness and Training.
VEGA:  A trained citizen spots the trick at the
gate before it opens.
VEGA:  In reality, that's security and privacy training so
people recognize and resist threats like phishing.
NOVA:  What is 'phishing,' exactly?
VEGA:  Bait for people. A message that looks legitimate
but is a trap - and it's how
most breaches actually begin.
NOVA:  How do you stop a perfect phishing email?
VEGA:  You train the human. AT-2 builds that instinct
in everyone - the instinct that hangs up
on the kind of call we opened with.
VEGA:  And AT-3 trains people for their particular role.
ARCHIVIST:  Provide security and privacy literacy training to system
users (including managers, senior executives, and contractors):
VEGA:  The cheapest firewall you own is an alert
human.
VEGA:  The Drillmaster's oath. The sharpest blade is an
alert mind.
VEGA:  The Oathkeeper, Personnel Security.
NULL:  Every guard you hire... could be mine.
VEGA:  In reality, that's screening people, adjusting access when
they move or leave, and guarding against insider
risk.
VEGA:  PS-3 screens people before they're trusted with access.
NOVA:  And when a guard leaves?
VEGA:  PS-4 reclaims the keys, on the way out
the door.
ARCHIVIST:  Upon termination of individual employment:
VEGA:  Access should follow the person, and leave when
they do.
VEGA:  The Oathkeeper's oath. Trust is earned at the
gate, and returned at the door.
VEGA:  The Privacy Herald, P-T, Processing and Transparency of
personal data.
NOVA:  New in Revision 5, privacy now stands beside
security.
VEGA:  In reality, that's processing people's personal data lawfully
and openly - with notice and consent where
required.
NOVA:  P-I-I keeps coming up.
VEGA:  Personally identifiable information - the data that points
to a real human being. Privacy is about
protecting it, and the person.
VEGA:  PT-2 demands a documented authority to process personal
data.
VEGA:  And PT-5 gives people honest notice of how
their data is used.
VEGA:  Authority first, then purpose and notice, then consent
where required, and process only as authorized.
NOVA:  Permission where needed, and honesty, before the data
is used.
ARCHIVIST:  Determine and document the [authority] that permits the
[processing] of personally identifiable information;
VEGA:  Security protects the data. Privacy honors the person.
VEGA:  The Privacy Herald's oath. By what right, for
what purpose, with whose leave?
VEGA:  Not every control is a firewall. Some are
a habit, a contract, a promise.
NOVA:  Scenario: a leaver kept their access. Which guardian
dropped the ball?
VEGA:  The answer is A.
VEGA:  And which guardian is the newcomer to the
catalog?
VEGA:  The answer is C.
NOVA:  Notebook: not every control is a firewall -
some are a habit, a contract, a promise.
VEGA:  People kept, the pact honored.
NULL:  Then I'll strike where no one is even
looking. Your plans.
VEGA:  Then it's time to meet the High Council.