NULL:  Every gap, every shortcut, every forgotten door -
I will find it.
VEGA:  Not tonight. And the deepest gaps aren't in
the walls - they're in the decisions above
them.
NOVA:  Decisions can be a vulnerability?
VEGA:  The costliest kind. Welcome to the High Council.
NULL:  Strike the plans, and every wall is built
on sand.
VEGA:  Then it's time you met the High Council,
where the realm is governed.
VEGA:  Layer four is governance, the decisions above any
single wall.
Four families rule the keep: Risk Assessment, Planning,
Program Management, and Assessment & Authorization.
NOVA:  RA, PL, PM, and CA. The seer, the
cartographer, the steward, and the inspector.
VEGA:  The Seer, Risk Assessment - though this seer
never merely guesses.
VEGA:  It doesn't read omens; it measures them: what
could go wrong, how likely, and how badly.
VEGA:  In reality, that's analyzing risk with hard evidence
- vulnerability scans and threat intelligence.
VEGA:  RA-3 is the formal risk assessment, the basis
for every choice.
NOVA:  How do we find the cracks before the
Null does?
VEGA:  RA-5, vulnerability monitoring and scanning, hunts them down.
ARCHIVIST:  Monitor and scan for vulnerabilities in the system
and hosted applications [organization-defined frequency and/or randomly in
accordance with organization-defined process] and when new vulnerabilities
potentially affecting the system are identified and reported;
VEGA:  Risk first. It tells you where to spend
your strength.
VEGA:  The Seer's oath. I do not guess the
storm; I measure it.
VEGA:  The Cartographer, Planning.
NOVA:  It draws the map of the defense before
the march.
VEGA:  In reality, that's the system security and privacy
plan, the rules of behavior, and the security
architecture.
VEGA:  PL-2 is the system security and privacy plan,
the master map.
VEGA:  And PL-8 plans the architecture, defense by design.
ARCHIVIST:  Develop security and privacy plans for the system
that:
VEGA:  No plan, no defense, just luck.
VEGA:  The Cartographer's oath. No march without a map.
VEGA:  The High Steward, Program Management.
VEGA:  It governs the whole realm's defense, above any
single system.
VEGA:  In reality, that's organization-wide governance: the security and
privacy program, roles, risk strategy, and resources.
NOVA:  Who sets the strategy for everything?
VEGA:  PM-9, the risk management strategy for the entire
organization.
VEGA:  Important: PM controls aren't selected per system from
a baseline.
VEGA:  They run across the whole organization, all the
time.
ARCHIVIST:  Develops a comprehensive strategy to manage:
VEGA:  Program management is the realm thinking as one.
VEGA:  The High Steward's oath. One realm, one strategy
- always.
VEGA:  The Inspector, Assessment, Authorization, and Monitoring.
NOVA:  It tests the defenses, and signs off before
the gates open.
VEGA:  In reality, that's assessing controls, formally authorizing a
system to operate, and watching it continuously.
VEGA:  CA-6, authorization, the authorizing official says 'I accept
this risk.' The agency we opened with ran
key systems without this signature.
NULL:  A signature won't stop me.
VEGA:  No. But it puts a name on the
wall the day something does. And CA-7 keeps
watching after the ink dries.
NOVA:  So a real person signs for the risk?
VEGA:  The authorizing official - a senior, accountable leader
- grants the A-T-O, and owns that decision.
VEGA:  CA-2 plans and runs the assessment, using procedures
from companion doc 800-53A.
NOVA:  And the gaps we find but can't close
today?
VEGA:  They go on the POA&M. CA-5 requires it,
and the authorizing official keeps an eye on
it.
ARCHIVIST:  Select the appropriate assessor or assessment team for
the type of assessment to be conducted;
VEGA:  Assess, authorize, and never stop monitoring.
VEGA:  The Inspector's oath. Test before you trust; watch
after you sign.
VEGA:  If a layer maps onto the framework, it's
this one.
NOVA:  Risk, planning, governance, and assessment, the work behind
the RMF lifecycle.
NOVA:  Scenario: go-live day. Whose signature is required? Pause,
and answer.
VEGA:  The answer is A.
VEGA:  And where do we record the gaps we
haven't closed yet?
VEGA:  The answer is B.
NOVA:  Notebook: this layer is the brain - it
decides what the walls are even for.
VEGA:  The realm is governed. Now, to where it's
all built.
NULL:  Built? I'll poison it at the source.
VEGA:  Then we descend to the Forge.