NULL:  Every gap, every shortcut, every forgotten door -
I will find it. Or I'll have you
build it for me.
VEGA:  Not tonight. We harden the forge itself -
how systems are built, configured, and supplied.
NOVA:  Even the parts we buy?
VEGA:  Especially those.
NULL:  Why break in, when I can be built
in? A flaw here, a tampered part there...
VEGA:  Then we harden the forge itself, where systems
are made and supplied.
VEGA:  Layer five is how you build, buy, configure,
maintain, and source.
Four families work the forge: System Acquisition, Configuration
Management, Maintenance, and Supply Chain Risk Management.
NOVA:  SA, CM, MA, and SR. The quartermaster, the
blueprint-master, the smith, and the caravan-master.
VEGA:  The Quartermaster, System and Services Acquisition.
VEGA:  It buys and builds only what can be
trusted.
VEGA:  In reality, that's building security into the development
life cycle, and into the systems and services
you acquire.
VEGA:  SA-8 builds security in by design, not as
an afterthought.
NOVA:  What about software no one updates anymore?
VEGA:  SA-22 says replace it, or arrange alternate support.
Unsupported is risk you must manage.
ARCHIVIST:  Apply the following systems security and privacy engineering
principles in the specification, design, development, implementation, and
modification of the system and system components:
VEGA:  Trust is forged in, never sprinkled on.
VEGA:  The Quartermaster's oath. Built in, never sprinkled on.
VEGA:  The Master of Blueprints, Configuration Management.
NULL:  One quiet, undocumented change... and I have a
door no one remembers.
VEGA:  In reality, that's keeping a known, approved configuration
and controlling every change, so systems stay in
a trusted state.
NOVA:  We already met 'baseline' back in Episode 00.
VEGA:  Different baseline. That was the control baseline. CM-2
is the configuration baseline - drift from it,
and you have a question to answer.
VEGA:  CM-2 holds the baseline, the master blueprint of
the system.
VEGA:  CM-7 is least functionality. Computers talk on numbered
channels - ports - and run background programs
- services.
NOVA:  And every one you don't need is another
door.
VEGA:  Exactly. CM-7 closes the ports and services you
never use.
ARCHIVIST:  Develop, document, and maintain under configuration control, a
current baseline configuration of the system;
VEGA:  A known system is a defensible system.
VEGA:  The Blueprint-Master's oath. A known system is a
defended system.
VEGA:  The Smith, Maintenance.
NOVA:  It tends the machinery, and watches who holds
the tools.
VEGA:  In reality, that's controlled system maintenance - including
safeguards for remote and third-party work.
VEGA:  MA-2 controls maintenance, scheduled, approved, and recorded.
NULL:  Your remote support line… I had such plans
for it.
VEGA:  MA-4 saw to that. Remote maintenance, tightly controlled.
ARCHIVIST:  Schedule, document, and review records of maintenance, repair,
and replacement on system components in accordance with
manufacturer or vendor specifications and/or organizational requirements;
VEGA:  Maintenance is access. Treat it like access.
VEGA:  The Smith's oath. Every tool is a key,
and I guard the keys.
VEGA:  The Caravan-Master, Supply Chain Risk Management, new in
Revision 5.
VEGA:  It guards the roads your supplies travel, all
the way to the source.
VEGA:  In reality, that's managing risk from suppliers and
components - the SolarWinds-style attack we opened with,
where a trusted update carried a hidden backdoor.
NOVA:  How do we trust the parts themselves?
VEGA:  SR-11, component authenticity, hunts counterfeits and tampering.
ARCHIVIST:  Develop and implement anti-counterfeit policy and procedures that
include the means to detect and prevent counterfeit
components from entering the system;
VEGA:  Your security is only as strong as your
weakest supplier.
VEGA:  The Caravan-Master's oath. I trust no part I
cannot trace.
VEGA:  The best breach is the one designed out
before it's built.
NOVA:  Scenario: a tampered part in the box. Whose
job is that? Pause, and answer.
A counterfeit network card arrives pre-tampered. Which control
should catch it?
Your options. A. CM-2 Baseline Configuration. B. SR-11
Component Authenticity. C. MA-2 Maintenance.
NOVA:  Pause here and lock in your answer.
VEGA:  The answer is B. SR-11 Component Authenticity. SR-11,
Component Authenticity, is aimed at catching counterfeit or
tampered parts.
VEGA:  And shutting the doors you never use?
Disabling unused ports and services is which control?
Your options. A. CM-7 Least Functionality. B. SA-22
Unsupported Components. C. CM-8 Inventory.
NOVA:  Pause here and lock in your answer.
VEGA:  The answer is A. CM-7 Least Functionality. CM-7,
Least Functionality, disables the ports, services, and features
you don't need.
NOVA:  Notebook: secure how you build, configure, maintain, and
source - the attacker counts on you skipping
one.
VEGA:  The forge is hardened, from source to system.
NULL:  Then I'll take your secrets in transit, or
your backups.
VEGA:  Then we ride for the Vaults and the
Lifelines.