NULL:  Every gap, every shortcut, every forgotten door -
I will find it. And if I can't
get in, I'll burn it down.
VEGA:  Not tonight. Seal the roads, guard the vaults,
and prepare for the dark.
NOVA:  Prepare for the worst, you mean.
VEGA:  Always.
NULL:  If I can't break the walls, I'll snatch
your secrets in transit, or wait for the
lights to go out.
VEGA:  Then we seal the roads, guard the vaults,
and prepare for the dark.
VEGA:  Layer six protects the data itself, and keeps
the city alive through disaster.
Three families hold the line: System & Communications
Protection, Media Protection, and Contingency Planning.
NOVA:  SC, MP, and CP. The warden of the
roads, the steward of scrolls, and the keeper
of lifelines.
VEGA:  The Warden of Walls and Roads, System and
Communications Protection.
VEGA:  It fortifies the ramparts and seals the roads
between districts.
VEGA:  In reality, that's boundary protection and cryptography -
guarding data as it moves and where it
rests.
NOVA:  What is 'the edge of the system'?
VEGA:  Draw a line around your computers, data, and
the people who run them. Inside is your
system. SC-7 watches that line.
VEGA:  SC-7, boundary protection, guards the edge of the
system.
NOVA:  You keep saying cryptography - what does it
actually do?
VEGA:  It locks the data. Encrypt it in transit
and at rest, and a thief without your
key gets nothing.
NULL:  I was listening on that line...
VEGA:  Then you heard noise. SC-8 protects data in
transit, often with approved cryptography.
NOVA:  And the data just sitting in storage?
VEGA:  SC-28 protects it at rest, often with cryptography
from SC-12 and SC-13.
VEGA:  Untrusted traffic meets the boundary, and only the
allowed passes through.
NOVA:  Filter at the edge, encrypt across the wire.
ARCHIVIST:  Monitor and control communications at the external managed
interfaces to the system and at key internal
managed interfaces within the system;
VEGA:  Protect data moving and still.
VEGA:  The Warden's oath. Filter at the edge; cipher
on the wire.
VEGA:  The Steward of Scrolls, Media Protection.
NOVA:  It guards every scroll, and destroys the ones
discarded.
VEGA:  By 'media,' NIST means storage: hard drives, SSDs,
tapes, USB sticks, even printed paper. MP protects
them - and wipes them before they're thrown
away.
VEGA:  MP-6, media sanitization, ensures deleted really means gone.
NULL:  Your old backup drive would have told me
everything.
VEGA:  And MP-7 controls removable media, the humble USB
stick.
VEGA:  One reading tip before the next gold card.
Notice the brackets in the catalog's text.
NOVA:  So the brackets are blanks the organization fills
in?
VEGA:  Exactly. The requirement is fixed; the value is
yours.
ARCHIVIST:  Sanitize [organization-defined system media] prior to disposal, release
out of organizational control, or release for reuse
using [organization-defined sanitization techniques and procedures] ;
VEGA:  Data outlives the device. Wipe it like you
mean it.
VEGA:  The Steward's oath. When it's gone, it's gone
for good.
VEGA:  The Keeper of Lifelines, Contingency Planning.
VEGA:  It plans for the day the towers fall,
and how to rebuild.
VEGA:  In reality, that's backups, alternate sites, and tested
plans to recover operations after a disruption.
NOVA:  What saves us from ransomware?
VEGA:  CP-9, system backup, a clean copy you can
actually restore.
VEGA:  'Clean' is the key word - a backup
kept offline or unchangeable, where ransomware can't reach
it. That's what saved the shipping line we
opened with.
VEGA:  CP-2 is the plan; CP-4 is the drill
that proves it works.
ARCHIVIST:  Conduct backups of user-level information contained in [system
components] [frequency];
VEGA:  Survival is planned in advance, never improvised.
VEGA:  The Keeper's oath. We rehearse the dark, so
we survive it.
VEGA:  Prevention buys time. Recovery buys survival.
NOVA:  Scenario: ransomware hits. What brings you home? Pause,
and answer.
Ransomware encrypts your servers. What gets you back
fastest?
Your options. A. A clean, tested backup (CP-9).
B. A firewall rule (SC-7). C. A privacy
notice (PT-5).
NOVA:  Pause here and lock in your answer.
VEGA:  The answer is A. A clean, tested backup
(CP-9). A clean, tested backup - CP-9 -
is what restores you fastest after ransomware.
VEGA:  And the drive that left with its secrets
intact?
A surplus hard drive is sold without being
wiped. Which control failed?
Your options. A. SC-8 Transmission. B. MP-6 Media
Sanitization. C. CP-2 Contingency Plan.
NOVA:  Pause here and lock in your answer.
VEGA:  The answer is B. MP-6 Media Sanitization. MP-6,
Media Sanitization, ensures drives are wiped before disposal
or reuse.
NOVA:  Notebook: lock the data moving and still -
and keep a backup the attacker can't touch.
VEGA:  Data sealed, lifelines ready. The city can take
a punch.
NULL:  Then I'll bring everything, all at once. Siege
night.
VEGA:  We'll be ready. All twenty guardians, together.