NULL:  Every gap, every shortcut, every forgotten door -
I will find it. Tonight, I bring everything.
Every vector, every door, all at once.
VEGA:  Not tonight. Tonight, every guardian answers. Welcome to
Siege Night.
VEGA:  One attacker, many weapons. One city, twenty guardians.
This is defense in depth.
He strikes everywhere at once. Watch the city
answer.
VEGA:  Each weapon meets a guardian. No single failure
ends the city.
NULL:  Repelled - this time. I just mapped every
lock you have. Next time, I bring the
right keys.
VEGA:  Layered defense means no single failure ends the
fight. If one layer fails, others still prevent,
detect, limit, or recover.
NOVA:  Twenty guardians, one shield.
VEGA:  Here is how it all comes together, the
lifecycle from 800-37.
VEGA:  Prepare, categorize, select, implement, assess, authorize, and monitor,
forever.
NOVA:  So in the real world, where do I
start?
VEGA:  Prepare, categorize the system, select and tailor a
baseline, implement, assess, authorize, and never stop watching.
VEGA:  These books travel together. Know which one answers
which question.
VEGA:  Hear the oaths together, and the whole defense
fits in your hand.
NOVA:  Twenty guardians, one shield.
NOVA:  Final test. Five questions, all twenty guardians. Ready?
NOVA:  One. Who checks your identity at the gate?
Which guardian proves you are who you claim,
before access?
Your options. A. AC - Access Control. B.
IA - Identification & Authentication. C. AU -
Audit.
NOVA:  Pause here and lock in your answer.
VEGA:  The answer is B. IA - Identification &
Authentication. Identification and Authentication proves identity before access
is granted.
NOVA:  Two. Where do the baselines live?
Where do the Low, Moderate, and High control
baselines live?
Your options. A. SP 800-53. B. SP 800-53B.
C. SP 800-53A.
NOVA:  Pause here and lock in your answer.
VEGA:  The answer is B. SP 800-53B. The baselines
live in companion volume 800-53B.
NOVA:  Three. What saves you from ransomware?
Ransomware hits and encrypts everything. What brings you
back?
Your options. A. CP-9 System Backup. B. AC-6
Least Privilege. C. AT-2 Training.
NOVA:  Pause here and lock in your answer.
VEGA:  The answer is A. CP-9 System Backup. CP-9,
System Backup, is what brings you back after
encryption.
NOVA:  Four. Which book holds the assessment procedures?
Which document tells you HOW to assess whether
controls work?
Your options. A. SP 800-53B. B. SP 800-53A.
C. FIPS 199.
NOVA:  Pause here and lock in your answer.
VEGA:  The answer is B. SP 800-53A. SP 800-53A
is the assessment companion - it tells you
HOW to test controls.
NOVA:  Five. Who signs to let the system go
live?
A senior official accepts the risk and lets
the system operate. Which control?
Your options. A. CA-6 Authorization. B. PL-2 System
Plan. C. RA-3 Risk Assessment.
NOVA:  Pause here and lock in your answer.
VEGA:  The answer is A. CA-6 Authorization. CA-6, Authorization,
is the official's formal acceptance of risk.
VEGA:  You walked every wall, every tower, every vault.
The siege broke on our walls, Nova.
NULL:  ...but I left with the blueprints. I'll be
back - and next time, it won't be
one city.
NOVA:  Then how do we prove a NEW citadel
is safe before we trust it with the
Crown Data?
VEGA:  That, apprentice, is a campaign. And in Act
Two, you're going to lead it.
The guardians are known. Now you learn to
deploy them - categorize, select, implement, assess, authorize,
and watch. The campaign begins in Act Two.