NULL:  Skip the owner, skip the sign-off - and
no one even knows I'm already inside.
VEGA:  Not here. Tonight we learn the framework that
makes someone accountable.
You have met the twenty guardians. But knowing
them is not the same as deploying them.
VEGA:  You just watched Aegis Hospital secured end to
end. Now we slow down and learn each
step - and Nova, you're leading it.
NOVA:  From apprentice to running the campaign. Let's begin.
VEGA:  The plan of campaign has a name: the
Risk Management Framework, from 800-37.
NOVA:  The process that tells you what to do,
and in what order.
NOVA:  What makes the RMF a 'framework' and not
just a checklist?
VEGA:  It's the living process that ties the catalog,
the baselines, and the assessments into one repeatable
lifecycle.
VEGA:  Seven steps. Prepare, categorize, select, implement, assess, authorize,
and monitor.
NOVA:  And it's a cycle, monitoring never stops.
VEGA:  Prepare was added in Revision 2, getting the
organization and system ready first.
VEGA:  Each step has a job, and most are
guided by a supporting NIST publication.
VEGA:  Authorize, then monitor. A system is never simply
'done.'
NULL:  Process. Paperwork. How quaint. I never sleep -
and your forms won't save you.
VEGA:  These books travel together. Each answers one question
in the campaign.
NOVA:  So Act One taught the controls. Act Two
is how we actually use them.
NOVA:  Quick check. How many steps in the framework?
Pause, and answer.
How many steps are in the RMF (SP
800-37 Rev 2)?
Your options. A. Five. B. Six. C. Seven.
NOVA:  Pause here and lock in your answer.
VEGA:  The answer is C. Seven. The RMF has
seven steps: Prepare, Categorize, Select, Implement, Assess, Authorize,
Monitor.
VEGA:  And which step did Revision 2 add at
the front?
Which RMF step was newly added in Revision
2?
Your options. A. Prepare. B. Authorize. C. Monitor.
NOVA:  Pause here and lock in your answer.
VEGA:  The answer is A. Prepare. Prepare is the
step added in RMF Revision 2.
VEGA:  The map is set. First stop, knowing what
we're protecting.
VEGA:  Next: categorization.