VEGA:  Before you pick defenses, you must know what
you're defending, and how much it matters.
This is categorization, and it begins with a
federal standard: FIPS 199.
NOVA:  FIPS? Categorize?
VEGA:  FIPS - Federal Information Processing Standards, the mandatory
ones. Categorizing is sizing the stakes for C,
I, and A - the triad from Episode
zero.
VEGA:  FIPS 199 judges a system on three objectives.
NOVA:  Confidentiality, Integrity, and Availability. The C-I-A triad.
VEGA:  For each objective, ask: how bad is the
worst-case impact?
VEGA:  Low, Moderate, or High.
NOVA:  So one High pulls the whole system up?
VEGA:  Exactly. We call it the high-water mark. The
worst case wins.
VEGA:  800-60 helps you rate each information type.
VEGA:  And FIPS 200 sets the floor, and points
you to 800-53.
VEGA:  And the catalog has a control for exactly
this: RA-2.
ARCHIVIST:  Categorize the system and information it processes, stores,
and transmits;
NOVA:  Scenario time. What's the overall category? Pause, and
answer.
VEGA:  The answer is C.
VEGA:  And which standard sets the impact levels themselves?
VEGA:  The answer is A.
VEGA:  We know the realm's worth. Now we choose
its defenses.
VEGA:  Next: the armory, and the baselines of 800-53B.