NULL:  Cut the control you find inconvenient. I'll be
waiting in the space it left.
VEGA:  Which is why every change is justified -
and the authorizing official signs for it.
VEGA:  You know the system's worth. Now draw your
loadout from the armory.
The baselines, and the tailoring guidance, live in
SP 800-53B.
NOVA:  So a baseline is a ready-made kit?
VEGA:  A starting kit. Matched to how much the
system matters.
NOVA:  Tailoring? Overlay?
VEGA:  Tailoring fits the kit to you - like
Aegis Hospital dropping wireless because that app is
wired-only, and adding a healthcare overlay. An overlay
is shared tailoring, so you don't start from
scratch.
VEGA:  Low draws 149 items. Moderate, 287. High, 370.
VEGA:  Higher impact, more controls and enhancements, by design.
VEGA:  A baseline is a starting point, never the
finish line. You tailor it to fit.
NULL:  I look for the control you wrongly tailored
away.
VEGA:  Overlays are shared tailoring, so you don't start
from scratch.
NOVA:  And remember, PM controls run across the whole
organization, outside any baseline.
NOVA:  Quick check. Which book holds the baselines? Pause,
and answer.
Where do the Low / Moderate / High
baselines live?
Your options. A. SP 800-53 (the catalog). B.
SP 800-53B. C. FIPS 199.
NOVA:  Pause here and lock in your answer.
VEGA:  The answer is B. SP 800-53B. The baselines
live in 800-53B; 800-53 holds the controls themselves.
VEGA:  And the act of adjusting the baseline to
fit your system?
Adjusting a baseline - scoping out, swapping, adding
controls - is called?
Your options. A. Categorization. B. Tailoring. C. Authorization.
NOVA:  Pause here and lock in your answer.
VEGA:  The answer is B. Tailoring. Adjusting a baseline
- scoping, swapping, adding - is tailoring, approved
by the authorizing official.
VEGA:  Defenses chosen and fitted. Now, do they actually
work?
VEGA:  Next: the reckoning, assessment and authorization.