VEGA:  The walls are built. But a defense you
haven't tested is only a hope.
Now: assessment, authorization, and the watch that never
ends.
VEGA:  800-53A gives assessors three methods.
NOVA:  Examine the evidence, interview the people, and test
the system itself.
VEGA:  The findings become a report, and every gap
gets a plan to close it.
VEGA:  Every step leaves a document. Together, they let
a leader make an honest call.
NOVA:  Assess, report, plan, package, authorize.
VEGA:  The catalog control behind all this is CA-2.
ARCHIVIST:  Select the appropriate assessor or assessment team for
the type of assessment to be conducted;
NOVA:  So someone has to own the risk and
sign for it?
VEGA:  Yes. The authorizing official grants the ATO, and
owns that decision.
NULL:  A signature... still won't stop me.
VEGA:  Which is why the final step never ends:
CA-7, continuous monitoring.
VEGA:  SP 800-137 is the playbook for that ongoing
watch.
NOVA:  Final stretch. Name the three assessment methods. Pause,
and answer.
VEGA:  The answer is B.
VEGA:  And the decision that lets the system go
live?
VEGA:  The answer is B.
VEGA:  And where do we track the gaps we
haven't closed?
VEGA:  The answer is B.
VEGA:  Categorize, select, implement, assess, authorize, monitor. You've walked
the whole campaign.
NOVA:  From a single control... to a system that's
authorized and watched for life.
NOVA:  In Episode zero, I didn't even know what
eight-hundred fifty-three was. Tonight, I'm signing for it.
VEGA:  Then sign, Castellan - and keep the watch.
NULL:  ...until next time.
NOVA:  There's always a next time. That's the job.
CA-7 - the watch never ends.
Episode zero promised: protect it, and you thrive.
You protected it. Now you never stop. The
story was ours; the controls are real.