VEGA:  Before we study the campaign step by step,
let's watch a real one unfold - start
to finish.
NOVA:  A real system? Not the metaphor?
VEGA:  A real system. And this time, apprentice, you're
running it.
VEGA:  Security isn't done by one hero. It's a
team: Maya owns the system day to day;
the CIO is the authorizing official who signs
for the risk; Raj is the hands-on security
officer; Sam guards the patients' privacy; and an
outside firm, Stellaris, assesses the work.
NOVA:  So 'doing 800-53' is really a group of
people, each with a named role and hat.
VEGA:  Here's our system. Not 'a computer' - an
app, a database, the staff who use it,
and the data they protect.
NOVA:  And those records are PII - personal, and
protected by law.
VEGA:  First, prepare - set roles and context. Then
categorize: how bad is the worst case for
C, I, and A?
VEGA:  Confidentiality, Moderate. But Integrity is High - a
wrong dose could kill. Availability is High -
downtime closes the ER.
NOVA:  And the high-water mark takes the worst of
the three...
VEGA:  So the whole system is categorized HIGH. One
High pulls it all up.
VEGA:  Maya opens 800-53B and draws the HIGH baseline
- and the privacy baseline, because of those
patient records.
NOVA:  A starting kit, sized to the stakes.
NOVA:  Does Maya's team really configure every one of
370 controls?
VEGA:  No. The data center already provides physical security,
PE-3, for every tenant. Maya inherits it -
that's a common control.
VEGA:  Tailoring is fitting the kit to the system
- not an excuse to delete protections.
NULL:  I look for the one control you wrongly
tailored away.
VEGA:  Which is why every change is justified and
written down - we drop wireless only because
this system has none.
VEGA:  Now Raj's team puts the controls to work.
The catalog says WHAT; they choose HOW.
NOVA:  Same requirement, many possible tools.
VEGA:  An outside assessor checks the work three ways:
examine, interview, test.
NOVA:  Selecting a control isn't proof it works. Assessment
is.
NOVA:  What about the weaknesses the assessor found?
VEGA:  The risk that remains - residual risk. The
CIO weighs it before anyone goes live.
VEGA:  The CIO signs the authorization to operate. Then
the watch begins - and never ends.
NULL:  Cute - a checklist against me? I live
in the gaps between your steps.
NOVA:  I just watched a whole system get secured,
start to finish.
VEGA:  You did. Now we'll slow down and learn
each step in depth - starting with the
framework itself.